<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="HB435C2605CC24D9A82B208CBEB280CF0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 9747 ENR: Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Eighteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Wednesday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-four</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 9747</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Making continuing appropriations and extensions for fiscal year 2025, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2DEE071AD7594DEC8FE5193A7719144F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7014086589F04D288B4D728A6F784262" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8792DD86877041AAA193F558A8C9B7D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of Contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H7014086589F04D288B4D728A6F784262" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8792DD86877041AAA193F558A8C9B7D3" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of Contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9E7889A358C04AD9B812764AD86734DE" level="section">Sec. 3. References.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE077A98249F44016B820682842FFFC49" level="division">Division A—Continuing Appropriations Act, 2025</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC23C97D075364CEAB922351BD2503472" level="division">Division B—Extensions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HAF2647933E5D4568BE07266FAB98A003" level="title">Title I—MISCELLANEOUS EXTENSIONS</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4F609D2C81874909BA8C3A38CC24078A" level="title">Title II—HEALTH EXTENDERS</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HFC79C92491AC47409822557F34A33413" level="title">Title III—VETERANS EXTENDERS</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB53337CB6E094AB3988A90EBCD0264CE" level="title">Title IV—BUDGETARY EFFECTS</toc-entry> </toc></section> 
<section id="H9E7889A358C04AD9B812764AD86734DE"><enum>3.</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as expressly provided otherwise, any reference to <quote>this Act</quote> contained in any division of this Act shall be treated as referring only to the provisions of that division.</text> </section> <division id="HE077A98249F44016B820682842FFFC49" style="appropriations"><enum>A</enum><header>Continuing Appropriations Act, 2025</header> <section id="H3609081A9DCE4B748473879D9BC9CEB8" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following sums are hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, and out of applicable corporate or other revenues, receipts, and funds, for the several departments, agencies, corporations, and other organizational units of Government for fiscal year 2025, and for other purposes, namely:</text></section> 
<section id="HEC075F80026345FDBB690A7A04CAB4D1"><enum>101.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such amounts as may be necessary, at a rate for operations as provided in the applicable appropriations Acts for fiscal year 2024 and under the authority and conditions provided in such Acts, for continuing projects or activities (including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees) that are not otherwise specifically provided for in this Act, that were conducted in fiscal year 2024, and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available in the following appropriations Acts:</text> <paragraph id="HCDE872DD509E4195B5CB652523FC37C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/42">Public Law 118–42</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8BC60778CB9458797A9D033ACDACC4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024 (division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/42">Public Law 118–42</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68895FD721E34562BD1444D2ACAA6682"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2024 (division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E19A3A9D0D24851ADAA106A2FF2DD32"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024 (division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/42">Public Law 118–42</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8F552A8BCD84C45929D5D7EC7297405"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2024 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>), except sections 637 and 638.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6E48BD32A5B4FD3832530738CA750A4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2024 (division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>), except section 546(e), and including sections 102 through 105 of title I of division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD9C61DE45BB43F6B3D44ABC4239AD56"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024 (division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/42">Public Law 118–42</external-xref>), except section 447.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30FA645BE36945568D33066842F23114"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024 (division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A20269B41D6425DBF1133909CF9D498"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2024 (division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>), except the matter under the heading <quote>Joint Items—Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies of 2025</quote>, and including section 7 in the matter preceding division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3743942DFC99449AB0B9B37675186CEF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024 (division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/42">Public Law 118–42</external-xref>), except section 259.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3D682B070E7444085ECF011CE55D66C"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>), except section 7075(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C19AF7520BA484D98DEBE78A04FC638"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/42">Public Law 118–42</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H3ABB49F6A82D47B5A44C5FA72B079372"><enum>102.</enum> <subsection id="H69CE9EBEBC87478580FFC647C4729480" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No appropriation or funds made available or authority granted pursuant to section 101 for the Department of Defense shall be used for:</text> 
<paragraph id="H54E85D5F52234B75A5FEEE678E3407A8" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the new production of items not funded for production in fiscal year 2024 or prior years;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB759809956594720954E7C34D72AEAEB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the increase in production rates above those sustained with fiscal year 2024 funds; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83748577F24647DF9ED69F0E707A4700" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the initiation, resumption, or continuation of any project, activity, operation, or organization (defined as any project, subproject, activity, budget activity, program element, and subprogram within a program element, and for any investment items defined as a P–1 line item in a budget activity within an appropriation account and an R–1 line item that includes a program element and subprogram element within an appropriation account) for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were not available during fiscal year 2024.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H087F50B51E9E42118220051FCD027353" indent="up1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No appropriation or funds made available or authority granted pursuant to section 101 for the Department of Defense shall be used to initiate multi-year procurements utilizing advance procurement funding for economic order quantity procurement unless specifically appropriated later.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6B5F6DF04AE349BF982B5B3A3362556E"><enum>103.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations made by section 101 shall be available to the extent and in the manner that would be provided by the pertinent appropriations Act.</text></section> <section id="H0A1039E34D954ADF9735FB7F3182A221"><enum>104.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in section 102, no appropriation or funds made available or authority granted pursuant to section 101 shall be used to initiate or resume any project or activity for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were not available during fiscal year 2024.</text></section> 
<section id="HDF3E3F36B88A46F79A39645920613DB8"><enum>105.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations made and authority granted pursuant to this Act shall cover all obligations or expenditures incurred for any project or activity during the period for which funds or authority for such project or activity are available under this Act.</text></section> <section id="HED40092838214637ADDD6A84667CB6BB"><enum>106.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise provided for in this Act or in the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2025, appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this Act shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2A184895AD0C40458C2D9A6641893F0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71AC5043420145849260C4C480543768"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2025 without any provision for such project or activity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D5FB3FBC82542DDB4AD2AF12A649A9D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>December 20, 2024.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H6DCB5B5C69BA4600AF923E5E385FEB15"><enum>107.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expenditures made pursuant to this Act shall be charged to the applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization whenever a bill in which such applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization is contained is enacted into law.</text></section> 
<section id="H90EF60CD58024E31B1C4C477E5873704"><enum>108.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations made and funds made available by or authority granted pursuant to this Act may be used without regard to the time limitations for submission and approval of apportionments set forth in section 1513 of title 31, United States Code, but nothing in this Act may be construed to waive any other provision of law governing the apportionment of funds.</text></section> <section id="H8C2BCCCCB1AA442EA3C69FE75B953135"><enum>109.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, except section 106, for those programs that would otherwise have high initial rates of operation or complete distribution of appropriations at the beginning of fiscal year 2025 because of distributions of funding to States, foreign countries, grantees, or others, such high initial rates of operation or complete distribution shall not be made, and no grants shall be awarded for such programs funded by this Act that would impinge on final funding prerogatives.</text></section> 
<section id="H346FAF9A84AA4BDDBF3868E59EE3C88E"><enum>110.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall be implemented so that only the most limited funding action of that permitted in the Act shall be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities.</text></section> <section id="HD96459E8709E4644A662315B9925AF00"><enum>111.</enum> <subsection id="HB260E4E7421B49F99DB2E3CD8742149A" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For entitlements and other mandatory payments whose budget authority was provided in appropriations Acts for fiscal year 2024, and for activities under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, activities shall be continued at the rate to maintain program levels under current law, under the authority and conditions provided in the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2024, to be continued through the date specified in section 106(3).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F4ED3FC91E94B97B4D1EFEAA8AB3B86"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 106, obligations for mandatory payments due on or about the first day of any month that begins after October 2024 but not later than 30 days after the date specified in section 106(3) may continue to be made, and funds shall be available for such payments.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H87CAAF264E8943DEA41B14177D948157"><enum>112.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available under section 101 for civilian personnel compensation and benefits in each department and agency may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to avoid furloughs within such department or agency, consistent with the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2024, except that such authority provided under this section shall not be used until after the department or agency has taken all necessary actions to reduce or defer non-personnel-related administrative expenses.</text></section> 
<section id="HE2F3D946FCD9402E9E3528A112BB794E"><enum>113.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated by this Act may be obligated and expended notwithstanding section 10 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/672">Public Law 91–672</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2412">22 U.S.C. 2412</external-xref>), section 15 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2680">22 U.S.C. 2680</external-xref>), section 313 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6212">22 U.S.C. 6212</external-xref>), and section 504(a)(1) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3094">50 U.S.C. 3094(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text></section> <section id="HEE1909E3F8434C82B37BAE83B15BCE0B"><enum>114.</enum> <subsection id="H958F89B342B94001943D4B77F0D14014" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each amount incorporated by reference in this Act that was previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 or as being for disaster relief pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(D) of such Act is designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of such Act or as being for disaster relief pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(D) of such Act, respectively.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6508F3C5A17B4DA1985D0F5BBBE8E14E"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6 of Public Laws 118–42 and 118–47 shall apply to amounts designated in subsection (a) and sections 138, 140, and 151 of this Act as an emergency requirement.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H44BDC7E709C14FEBB50B5BD1EC2FD7DF"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each amount incorporated by reference in this Act that was previously designated in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/159">Public Law 117–159</external-xref>, division J of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>, or in section 443(b) of division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref> by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget shall continue to be treated as an amount specified in section 103(b) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/5">Public Law 118–5</external-xref>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF18C41EFF9744C259D34F72B3435488C"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall become effective immediately upon enactment of this Act, and shall remain in effect through the date in section 106(3).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC312E942F9CE4EE3939993A1457BB304"><enum>115.</enum> <subsection id="HA513EDAD02F443DEAACA16A14DAEE446" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rescissions or cancellations of discretionary budget authority that continue pursuant to section 101 in Treasury Appropriations Fund Symbols (TAFS)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4290307BC65D49D1B6FBC0A95FC58CE9" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to which other appropriations are not provided by this Act, but for which there is a current applicable TAFS that does receive an appropriation in this Act; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC1C1AA3FD394CACB1243CE9240CD053" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which are no-year TAFS and receive other appropriations in this Act, may be continued instead by reducing the rate for operations otherwise provided by section 101 for such current applicable TAFS, as long as doing so does not impinge on the final funding prerogatives of the Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD21C6B7178AE49FBB1BFE4F3F3A1AD50" indent="up1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rescissions or cancellations described in subsection (a) shall continue in an amount equal to the lesser of—</text> <paragraph id="H747E12C9D5964E42BCC0F862BE3C3165"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount specified for rescission or cancellation in the applicable appropriations Act referenced in section 101 of this Act; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3346DE2F200849299CD57EDA45034574"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of balances available, as of October 1, 2024, from the funds specified for rescission or cancellation in the applicable appropriations Act referenced in section 101 of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD91F0D90198547DBA353CD3F6C70FDE5" indent="up1"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No later than November 18, 2024, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall provide to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a comprehensive list of the rescissions or cancellations that will continue pursuant to section 101: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the information in such comprehensive list shall be periodically updated to reflect any subsequent changes in the amount of balances available, as of October 1, 2024, from the funds specified for rescission or cancellation in the applicable appropriations Act referenced in section 101, and such updates shall be transmitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate upon request.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H871FEFFEDDCC4927A87B8AB2A6C7AB1A"><enum>116.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 for <quote>Farm Service Agency—Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund Program Account</quote> may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to accommodate approved applications for direct and guaranteed farm ownership loans, as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1922">7 U.S.C. 1922 et seq.</external-xref>, and direct farm operating loans, as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1941">7 U.S.C. 1941 et seq.</external-xref></text></section> <section id="H655894CBC32041BA856225E5D204C05D"><enum>117.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 for <quote>Rural Housing Service—Rural Community Facilities Program Account</quote> may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to maintain activities as authorized by section 306 and described in section 381E(d)(1) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act.</text></section> 
<section id="HC489BB3930874999A3FB610EB0412454"><enum>118.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 for <quote>Domestic Food Programs—Food and Nutrition Service—Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC)</quote> may be apportioned at the rate for operations necessary to maintain participation.</text></section> <section id="H93F918CFA48F45E294493FE8456CE661"><enum>119.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 for <quote>Domestic Food Programs—Food and Nutrition Service—Commodity Assistance Program</quote> may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to maintain current program caseload in the Commodity Supplemental Food Program.</text></section> 
<section id="HFCE037F0CD874AC9BD18DBEE32BC40E1"><enum>120.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 260 of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1636i">7 U.S.C. 1636i</external-xref>) and section 942 of the Livestock Mandatory Reporting Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1635">7 U.S.C. 1635</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/78">Public Law 106–78</external-xref>) shall be applied by substituting the date specified in section 106(3) of this Act for <quote>September 30, 2024</quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCAABB94CA42E4B0DA9EF8E7A54557E38"><enum>121.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period covered by this Act, section 235(b) of the Sentencing Reform Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/3551">18 U.S.C. 3551</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/473">Public Law 98–473</external-xref>; 98 Stat. 2032), as such section relates to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/311">chapter 311</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, and the United States Parole Commission, shall be applied by substituting <quote>37</quote> for <quote>36</quote> each place it appears.</text></section> 
<section id="HF51BF31DF2AC4DCABEF59CD5ED33875A"><enum>122.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 104, amounts made available by section 101 for <quote>Corps of Engineers—Civil—Operation and Maintenance</quote> may be used up to an amount not to exceed $37,600,000, adjusted for inflation beginning August 1, 2024, to provide compensation for reserving and operating 3.6 million acre-feet of pre-planned flood storage at Hugh Keenleyside Dam to minimize the flood risk in the Columbia River Basin in the United States.</text></section> <section id="HFE1B1CF86C474352B2A15483D7D33368"><enum>123.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period covered by this Act, section 3 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/392">Public Law 106–392</external-xref> shall be applied by substituting <quote>2025</quote> for <quote>2024</quote> each place it appears.</text></section> 
<section id="H96D3CA9621EC4FECA51E19C7A6A1727B"><enum>124.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 106, for the duration of fiscal year 2025, amounts made available under section 601(f)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/801">42 U.S.C. 801(f)(3)</external-xref>) shall be available for any necessary expenses of the Department of the Treasury Office of Inspector General with respect to section 601 of such Act, subtitle A of title V of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021, or section 3201 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021, in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes.</text></section> <section id="HDD2948B86A6A473A95C8F943D0285493"><enum>125.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 101, for <quote>Executive Office of the President—Office of Administration—Presidential Transition Administrative Support</quote>, there is appropriated $25,000,000 for an additional amount for fiscal year 2025, to remain available until September 30, 2025, to carry out the Presidential Transition Act of 1963 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/3/102">3 U.S.C. 102</external-xref> note) and similar expenses, in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such funds may be transferred to other accounts (including other agencies) that provide support to offices within the Executive Office of the President and the Office of the Vice President, to carry out such purposes, including to reimburse obligations incurred prior to the enactment of this Act for such purposes.</text></section> 
<section id="H47255779902F422C87F536FE272FBE5F"><enum>126.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise provided by section 101, amounts are provided for <quote>District of Columbia—Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia</quote> at a rate for operations of $47,000,000, for an additional amount for costs associated with the Presidential Inauguration to be held in January 2025: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amounts may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to maintain emergency planning and security activities relating to such Presidential Inauguration.</text></section> <section id="HA3C3D54AB3BA4DA4AEC7D80247348572"><enum>127.</enum> <subsection id="HEAEC294740EC417AA2A7F1EDF42C59C3" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The matter preceding the first proviso under the heading <quote>Federal Payment to the District of Columbia Public Defender Service</quote> in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>, for costs associated with relocation under a replacement lease for headquarters offices, field offices, and related facilities</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAA0DB8756F4647648411B99FBB0D1717"><enum>(b)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H8F0072CCD0E04858A18DC48514AA4625" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), subsection (a) shall become effective immediately upon enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A0C5153D4954B49B96A1FDF1755A832" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If this Act is enacted after September 30, 2024, subsection (a) shall be applied as if it were in effect on September 30, 2024.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H73161A3BC12C42628A31207A45B829B0"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 101, the matter preceding the first proviso under the heading <quote>Federal Payment to the District of Columbia Public Defender Service</quote> in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>, as amended by subsection (a), shall be applied as if <quote>, of which $3,000,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2026</quote> were struck.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H8FE5D9DFF301408EB8D6571BE3CEA6A7"><enum>128.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, except section 106, the District of Columbia may expend local funds made available under the heading <quote>District of Columbia—District of Columbia Funds</quote> for such programs and activities under the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2024 (title IV of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>) at the rate set forth in the Fiscal Year 2025 Local Budget Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25–501), as modified as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="HAE43D543616344D18669C03827059A33"><enum>129.</enum> 
<subsection id="H0005C8E617974A8882987FBEB1F78261" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 101, for <quote>General Services Administration—Expenses, Presidential Transition</quote>, there is appropriated $19,424,177, for an additional amount for fiscal year 2025, to remain available until September 30, 2025, for necessary expenses to carry out the Presidential Transition Act of 1963 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/3/102">3 U.S.C. 102</external-xref> note), of which $14,443,726 is available for activities authorized by sections 3(a)(1) through 3(a)(7) and 3(a)(10) of such Act; $2,980,451 is available for activities authorized by section 5 of such Act; and $2,000,000 is available for activities authorized by sections 3(a)(8) and 3(a)(9) of such Act: <italic>Provided</italic>, That if there are two or more possible apparent successful candidates, each such candidate, with the exception of the incumbent President, is entitled to a proportional share of the appropriations made available for activities authorized by sections 3(a)(1) through 3(a)(7) and 3(a)(10) and sections 3(a)(8) and 3(a)(9) of such Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That no apparent successful candidate shall receive more than $7,221,863 for activities authorized by sections 3(a)(1) through 3(a)(7) and 3(a)(10) of such Act and $1,000,000 for activities authorized by sections 3(a)(8) and 3(a)(9) of such Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amounts may be transferred and credited to the <quote>Acquisition Services Fund</quote> or the <quote>Federal Buildings Fund</quote> to reimburse obligations incurred prior to enactment of this Act for the purposes provided herein related to the Presidential election in 2024: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That in the case of two or more possible apparent successful candidates, after a sole apparent successful candidate is determined, the remaining funds allotted to any unsuccessful candidate shall be permanently rescinded: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That amounts available under this section shall be in addition to any other amounts available for such purposes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H873F545780A94EE99066724E3DD83DDF"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 101, no funds are provided by this Act for <quote>General Services Administration—Pre-Election Presidential Transition</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6A62A30452D94D0D935BF9B3E194207F"><enum>130.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise provided by section 101, for <quote>National Archives and Records Administration—Operating Expenses</quote>, there is appropriated $23,000,000, for an additional amount for fiscal year 2025, to remain available until September 30, 2025, to carry out transition responsibilities of the Archivist of the United States under sections 2201 through 2209 of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Presidential Records Act of 1978</quote>), in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes.</text></section> <section id="HF01E3197E69C4FF4BD9A41973F2A18C7"><enum>131.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 101, the matter preceding the first proviso under the heading <quote>Office of Personnel Management—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref> shall be applied by substituting <quote>$190,784,000</quote> for <quote>$219,076,000</quote> and the second proviso under such heading in such division of such Act shall be applied by substituting <quote>$245,267,000</quote> for <quote>$192,975,000</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HAAE7FE8DEA9F4568896B0B8E283CA86D"><enum>132.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 104, amounts made available by section 101 to the Department of Homeland Security for <quote>Coast Guard—Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> may be used for closeout costs relating to the C–27J missionization program.</text></section> <section id="H487C1F629BEA424C80A1BB868716DA60"><enum>133.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period covered by this Act, section 11223(b)(2) of division K of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref> shall be applied by substituting <quote>shall not apply</quote> for <quote>shall apply</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H99709E447BA14E77936181FB3FEC2F25"><enum>134.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 to the Department of Homeland Security under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Disaster Relief Fund</quote> may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to carry out response and recovery activities under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section> <section id="H10875D46282E418EBEB97674B64A35B8"><enum>135.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 to the Department of Homeland Security for <quote>United States Secret Service—Operations and Support</quote> may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to carry out protective operations, including activities related to National Special Security Events and the 2024 Presidential Campaign.</text></section> 
<section id="H732BF8C530994426A4E0838A9991E3C7" commented="no"><enum>136.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise provided by section 101, there is appropriated to the Department of Homeland Security for <quote>United States Secret Service—Operations and Support</quote>, $231,000,000, for an additional amount for fiscal year 2025, to remain available until September 30, 2025, for operations necessary to carry out protective operations including the 2024 Presidential Campaign and National Special Security Events: <italic>Provided</italic>, That not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the United States Secret Service shall provide to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate an expenditure plan that identifies, by program, project, and activity, the funding obligated for the purposes specified in this section with amounts for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> in this Act and shall provide to the Committees monthly reports on the execution of such expenditure plan: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amounts may not be obligated until the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security transmits to the House of Representatives Task Force on the Attempted Assassination of Donald J. Trump and the Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs the Mission Assurance Report: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That within 15 days of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security shall provide to the House of Representatives Task Force on the Attempted Assassination of Donald J. Trump all materials responsive to such Task Force’s letters transmitted on August 12, 2024, and August 28, 2024: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Director of the Secret Service shall respond in a timely manner to oversight inquiries (including requests for documents, information, and testimony from any Secret Service personnel) on protective operations funded in this Act or in <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref> from the House of Representatives Task Force on the Attempted Assassination of Donald J. Trump; the Committees on Appropriations, Homeland Security, Oversight and Accountability, and Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and the Committees on Appropriations, Judiciary, and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, or any subcommittees thereof: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That responses shall be considered timely if provided on or before the deadline specified by the requesting committee or subcommittee.</text></section> <section id="H70172033380648709EF99A45D9473129"><enum>137.</enum> <subsection id="H87C80EED67984207BC133EA773571B7D" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 1309(a) and 1319 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4016">42 U.S.C. 4016(a)</external-xref> and 4026) shall be applied by substituting the date specified in section 106(3) of this Act for <quote>September 30, 2023</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H87961A9CE6944693B0706CA6F814B99E"><enum>(b)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H3FD253A09498475882B2506935BFB6AF" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), this section shall become effective immediately upon enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H532A1D29DC954546B4946A472CF5328C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If this Act is enacted after September 30, 2024, this section shall be applied as if it were in effect on September 30, 2024.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA39448C37DC24114A2EF4EC696DE3524" commented="no"><enum>138.</enum> 
<subsection id="HF512307C25A24FC5BE54DEB27671C595" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period covered by this Act, section 104 of the Hermit’s Peak/Calf Canyon Fire Assistance Act (division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/180">Public Law 117–180</external-xref>) shall be applied by substituting the date specified in section 106(3) of this Act for “2 years after the date on which regulations are first promulgated under subsection (f)”, and “May 31, 2024”.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H82CD688483954BEFAB6FD68F75F83F15" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts repurposed pursuant to this section that were previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 or a concurrent resolution on the budget are designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="HC089CD03E82E4AABAF1F916229C322F0"><enum>139.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise provided by section 101, amounts are provided for <quote>Department of the Interior—National Park Service—Operation of the National Park System</quote> at a rate for operations of $5,000,000, for an additional amount for security and visitor safety activities related to the Presidential Inaugural Ceremonies.</text></section> <section id="H31F42022114F4A16834DA4132EAD1C37"><enum>140.</enum> <subsection id="H426D0460FB3F4A2F8441C5E47726BBC0" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds previously made available in the Further Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2018 (subdivision 1 of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</external-xref>) for the <quote>National Park Service—Historic Preservation Fund</quote> that were available for obligation through fiscal year 2019 are to remain available through fiscal year 2026 for the liquidation of valid obligations incurred in fiscal years 2018 and 2019: <italic>Provided</italic>, That amounts repurposed pursuant to this section that were previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 are designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H93578D4AC4FB4AC694839F89B5B87276"><enum>(b)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H4255770ECE9B4D23836FBB958C7968E8" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), this section shall become effective immediately upon enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CD2E18FF2D34B9DABE366FB6EA0C312" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If this Act is enacted after September 30, 2024, this section shall be applied as if it were in effect on September 30, 2024.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H521D917B727543688749AAF63EAB0DA2"><enum>141.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 for <quote>Department of Agriculture—Forest Service—Wildland Fire Management</quote> may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary for wildfire suppression activities.</text></section> <section id="HB488A19DE75A4543A02DAE501AD1ACF0"><enum>142.</enum> <subsection id="H4C01467E2F334E3493A3C42F2432101C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise provided by section 101, amounts are provided for <quote>Department of Health and Human Services—Indian Health Service—Indian Health Services</quote> at a rate for operations of $24,262,000, for an additional amount for costs of staffing and operating facilities that were opened, renovated, or expanded in fiscal years 2024 and 2025, and such amounts may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to staff and operate such facilities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC41BC403A7E44D7899EE71129FC14B1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise provided by section 101, amounts are provided for <quote>Department of Health and Human Services—Indian Health Service—Indian Health Facilities</quote> at a rate for operations of $2,060,000, for an additional amount for costs of staffing and operating facilities that were opened, renovated, or expanded in fiscal years 2024 and 2025, and such amounts may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to staff and operate such facilities.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H23E4D4D169184904974FCEA5B44586F4"><enum>143.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period covered by this Act, section 113 of division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>, as amended by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/6">Public Law 116–6</external-xref>, shall be applied by substituting <quote>2025</quote> for <quote>2024</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H483BD9EA667E4943B2240916A42626C8"><enum>144.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise provided by section 101, amounts are provided for <quote>Department of Labor—Bureau of Labor Statistics—Salaries and Expenses</quote> at a rate for operations of $6,000,000, for an additional amount for the Current Population Survey.</text></section> <section id="H4361B2DF98F442A7A853BC218B6BC4F7"><enum>145.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities authorized by part A of title IV (other than under section 403(c) or 418) and section 1108(b) of the Social Security Act shall continue through the date specified in section 106(3), in the manner authorized for fiscal year 2024, and out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are hereby appropriated such sums as may be necessary for such purpose.</text></section> 
<section id="H9A6EBC1FFCEC422EBC1F5290E304DB5A"><enum>146.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, there is appropriated—</text> <paragraph id="H203D5E6FB9034FA7B5AF4F6F0348DCE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for payment to the heirs at law of Sheila Jackson Lee, late a Representative from the State of Texas, $174,000;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA4D7C940E7E24CDFA49E8F53982551F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for payment to Elsie M. Pascrell, widow of William Pascrell, Jr., late a Representative from the State of New Jersey, $174,000; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7503465F29A4504BB76E9AFF526E32F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for payment to Beatrice Y. Payne, widow of Donald M. Payne, Jr., late a Representative from the State of New Jersey, $174,000.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HD8CE9ED005C44E49B0213ADC30036F7B"><enum>147.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding sections 102 and 104, amounts made available by section 101 to the Department of Defense for <quote>Military Construction, Navy</quote> may be used by the Secretary of the Navy to carry out military construction not otherwise authorized by law for a Trident Refit Facility project at Naval Submarine Base Kings Bay.</text></section> <section id="HCBFCFB8F368548578B8B08AB34EB9D8F"><enum>148.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 101, section 126 of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/42">Public Law 118–42</external-xref> shall be applied by substituting <quote>fiscal year 2017, 2018, 2019, and 2020</quote> for <quote>fiscal year 2017, 2018, and 2019</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H5EB1DBEA88944D4F816B2B2BF9359B8F"><enum>149.</enum> 
<subsection id="HBB69D59BBFE24A9EAA829C279F3BF4FE" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The remaining unobligated balances as of September 30, 2024, from amounts made available until September 30, 2024, for <quote>Departmental Administration—Construction, Major Projects</quote> in title II of division F of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>) are hereby rescinded, and in addition to amounts otherwise provided by section 101, an amount of additional new budget authority equivalent to the amount rescinded pursuant to this section is hereby appropriated on September 30, 2024, for an additional amount for fiscal year 2024, to remain available until September 30, 2029, and shall be available for the same purposes and under the same authorities provided under such heading in <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>, in addition to other funds as may be available for such purposes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD86B8A823ED143BB919B547C6CBE01B9"><enum>(b)</enum> <paragraph id="H7E64AF45F4914555B312CE35C1A6806B" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), this section shall become effective immediately upon enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3D865E953E940ED972C5027C5F9A85B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If this Act is enacted after September 30, 2024, this section shall be applied as if it were in effect on September 30, 2024.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H67FFAFA69352492BB53E25E01C6B4CF0"><enum>150.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 for <quote>Department of Transportation—Office of the Secretary—Payments to Air Carriers</quote> may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to maintain Essential Air Service program operations.</text></section> 
<section id="HF96D519D36794E78A5D1F3C8ED1BD3A8"><enum>151.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period covered by this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may use the unobligated balances of amounts made available in prior fiscal years in the second paragraph under the heading <quote>Department of Housing and Urban Development—Public and Indian Housing—Tenant-Based Rental Assistance</quote> to support additional allocations under subparagraph (D) of paragraph (1) and subparagraph (B) of paragraph (4) of such heading to prevent the termination of rental assistance for families as a result of insufficient funding in the calendar year 2024 funding cycle: <italic>Provided</italic>, That amounts repurposed pursuant to this section that were previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></section> <section id="H4A5C36703E214BBCB87C823F1D715C78"><enum>152.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period covered by this Act, section 517 of title 10, United States Code, shall not apply with respect to the Coast Guard.</text></section> 
<section section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15B5A3147DFB4E10A6F2227AAE3BFC66"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This division may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Continuing Appropriations Act, 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section></division> <division id="HC23C97D075364CEAB922351BD2503472"><enum>B</enum><header>Extensions</header> <title id="HAF2647933E5D4568BE07266FAB98A003" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>MISCELLANEOUS EXTENSIONS</header> <section id="HF3915550011D44BB944A17AA2B90A6F7" commented="no"><enum>101.</enum><header>Protection of certain facilities and assets from unmanned aircraft</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 210G(i) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124n">6 U.S.C. 124n(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>October 1, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote>. </text></section> 
<section id="HECAE824290EF4A83906D0CD78CB3EF91"><enum>102.</enum><header>Joint Task Forces</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 708(b)(13) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/348">6 U.S.C. 348(b)(13)</external-xref>) shall be applied by substituting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote> for <quote>September 30, 2024</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H370EA4F75AC341D9BD8B38A5967B9E94"><enum>103.</enum><header>National Cybersecurity Protection System Authorization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 227(a) of the Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1525">6 U.S.C. 1525(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H6AD4182037E747DB8BE747DB68EC476F" commented="no"><enum>104.</enum><header>Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historical Park Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6(g) of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/410y-4">16 U.S.C. 410y–4(g)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>40</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>on December 20, 2024.</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H024873B811EC43F092E39CF5B1E73463"><enum>105.</enum><header>EBT benefit fraud prevention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 501 of division HH of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2016a">7 U.S.C. 2016a</external-xref>), is amended—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H123D8068066D4738A6B55D6A0749AC52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H8468116A74234DE9B1A91EB97974310C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A)(iii), by striking <quote>to the maximum extent practicable,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC893AF1FB12C477B95A4BD055DD110B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text> <clause id="H6A93D6FDED05468B9D36686EEFC10FA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>October</quote> and inserting <quote>December</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5CE9806F2C7948B5A7C5B98E9CE0C83D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>to the maximum extent practicable,</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HADF75B7C908947459C519B436C317D9E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H704A6FE156A44DA8A4C048209F5DFA72"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E);</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5808D13FEE384B37BD86FCE4BDE71896"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB50EE1A0FDD494EB97AE08AD912AB39"> 
<subparagraph id="H1328EE975043468B8170E0772769AD3E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a comparison of State plans related to reimbursement, prevention, and other relevant procedures approved in accordance with subsection (b)(1)(A); and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H782CCD5C85F0491987992C8A6322A600"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E) (as so redesignated), by inserting <quote>and proactively</quote> after <quote>consistently</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5679CA7E4154B2DA2CABDF5F5B68DE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(C), by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4AF5C15DA2A1485A90EBC76D0CD59105"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EE25162A4264887B1E4CB516D676F73"> 
<subsection id="H15B5F6647DA1463292922BBFF16EDFFC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Comptroller general</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9E3F16A96AB46369CD49F536F0DAAA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report that examines risks related to supplemental nutrition assistance program electronic benefit transfer payment system security, including the risk of stolen benefits through card skimming, card cloning, and other similar methods.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC106A9A386B849F794E9FDFBB3ED433A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report under paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H07D2953B87594AD69BC19319DA210E06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which the Department of Agriculture manages payment system security, including risks related to stolen benefits, compared to leading industry practices;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0670936B5B24357A7B3BA7E24A49EFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the manner in which States, retailers, and other relevant entities manage risks related to stolen benefits;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C92EE86131F4DA2B9DADD632A12537A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the oversight of and guidance provided by the Secretary to States regarding stolen benefits; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFAD20A84490945A99720E1D76CAAB781"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations and policy options for—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6081348DF7504700B4E85749DA9FB38F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving how the Department of Agriculture and other relevant entities manage payment system security risks, including those related to stolen benefits; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E4F023F8FD84EE28C843ADCCD20EF5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the Department of Agriculture may best share those improvements with States, retailers, and other relevant entities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EA5B72AB0C24BAC8E7B094E48581B1E"><enum>106.</enum><header>Extension of Forest Service Participation in ACES Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8302(b) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3851a">16 U.S.C. 3851a(b)</external-xref>) shall be applied by substituting <quote>1 day after December 20, 2024</quote> for <quote>October 1, 2023</quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H2B20AC032539410E8026AFF960F6B143"><enum>107.</enum><header>Extension of Good Neighbor Authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8206(b)(2)(C)(ii) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2113a">16 U.S.C. 2113a(b)(2)(C)(ii)</external-xref>) shall be applied by substituting <quote>1 day after December 20, 2024</quote> for <quote>October 1, 2024</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HA5101495EE1F4DE7882409C397965804"><enum>108.</enum><header>Temporary extension of Food for Peace Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authorities provided by each provision of the Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1691">7 U.S.C. 1691 et seq.</external-xref>), as in effect on September 30, 2024, shall remain in effect through December 20, 2024.</text></section> <section id="H46B522EC339B4D228EB020BE5CEC1D8D" commented="no"><enum>109.</enum><header>Overseas pay comparability and limitation</header> <subsection id="H4FCE85D0354840748063DD4C089F5379" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authority provided under section 1113 of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/32">Public Law 111–32</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1904) shall remain in effect through December 20, 2024.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F2A5E36AD23439EBF5CCB8DF953863A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The authority described in subsection (a) may not be used to pay an eligible member of the Foreign Service (as defined in section 1113(b) of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/32">Public Law 111–32</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1904)) a locality-based comparability payment (stated as a percentage) that exceeds two-thirds of the amount of the locality-based comparability payment (stated as a percentage) that would be payable to such member under section 5304 of title 5, United States Code, if such member’s official duty station were in the District of Columbia.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA1CF72E45D344A4AB455E07194CD80C6" commented="no"><enum>110.</enum><header>Provisions related to the compact of free association with the Republic of Palau</header> <subsection id="HE2E349C5B81248EF988AF5426CA78ADC" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal programs and services agreement with the Government of the Republic of Palau</header><text>During the period beginning on October 1, 2024, and ending on the date on which a new Federal programs and services agreement with the Government of the Republic of Palau enters into force, any activities described in sections 132 and 221(a) of the Compact of Free Association between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of Palau set forth in section 201 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/99/658">Public Law 99–658</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/1931">48 U.S.C. 1931</external-xref> note) shall, with the mutual consent of the Government of the Republic of Palau, continue in the manner authorized and required for fiscal year 2024 under the amended agreements described in subsections (b) and (f) of section 462 of that Compact.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5A69DC99E41B4B39998B4FAB03F62F4B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments related to the 2024 Federal programs and services agreement with the Republic of Palau</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H532F122C79824C83B5DF411B88C0A909"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 204(e) of the Compact of Free Association Amendments Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/1983">48 U.S.C. 1983(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87AEAA009B3245E7B600A7C9A44D7749"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4), by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H924275E97D044A8EACF93CB26590DD56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (4) as subparagraphs (A) through (D), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BC8F53E87854A52A22D55FAB14BA0A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>An agreement</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H166619CC66AC4682996E5543565C6B30"> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H443CA3B7FDDC483C9C6EC5CEBE0EA998"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An agreement</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B718A1D70B6491CABE4F09A6A933791"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF12F70931C124982995AAC4C0C9ABA56"> 
<paragraph id="H174327A78DB44E0AA32EEBEDA2EDA8C3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal Programs and Services Agreement with the Republic of Palau</header><text>Subparagraphs (A) and (D)(iii) of section 101(c)(2) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/99/658">Public Law 99–658</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/1931">48 U.S.C. 1931(c)(2)</external-xref>) and subsection (d)(2)(A) shall not apply to an agreement that would amend, change, or terminate the agreement described in section 462(f) of the U.S.-Palau Compact.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7345FE9A1AEB49798348CAF440048915"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 210(a)(2) of the Compact of Free Association Amendments Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/1989">48 U.S.C. 1989(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9094CA149444C78BDD04AFEF5E389FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6355EE16432E43C3B0B25E79B81249E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (F); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB379BC5FA53545E8A723B411239361BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E8E302983FC4C679D59496D4E1FC770"> <subparagraph id="H41B8209F67A24107823C0686EE1E5339" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>with respect to the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, any applicable Federal programs and services agreement between the United States and the Republic of Palau; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H63CC5A713E554E4CBA7D0E59374EAA17" commented="no"><enum>111.</enum><header>United States Agency for International Development Civil Service annuitant waiver</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 625(j)(1)(B) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2385">22 U.S.C. 2385(j)(1)(B)</external-xref>) shall be applied by striking <quote>October 1, 2010</quote> and inserting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H280280B7815A4C6197455AC81F475D5B" commented="no"><enum>112.</enum><header>United States Agency for International Development Inspector General annuitant waiver</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authorities provided under section 1015(b) of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/212">Public Law 111–212</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 2332)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H075226C37F1B4FD5BECF3DAA8D71CAD0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall remain in effect through December 20, 2024; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC365EE3165F441879A15384A1140D1A2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may be used to facilitate the assignment of persons for oversight of programs in countries with a humanitarian disaster or complex emergency declaration.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H17A7CBB1E534439687132C8E137E1695" commented="no"><enum>113.</enum><header>Extension of Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act of 2019</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7(h) of the Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/76">Public Law 116–76</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/5701">22 U.S.C. 5701</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H07B2FD46D95540D2B8ED0D2B107DAC90" commented="no"><enum>114.</enum><header>Extension of transfers of air traffic systems acquired with AIP funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 728(b) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/63">Public Law 118–63</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>October 1, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote>.</text></section></title> 
<title id="H4F609D2C81874909BA8C3A38CC24078A" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>HEALTH EXTENDERS</header> 
<subtitle id="H8B3F6A33F5A34EF99BCC2D6F7B41BDCA" style="OLC"><enum>A</enum><header>Public Health</header> 
<section id="H905DF35E1DB94E47B34FCDB3CCDB6445"><enum>201.</enum><header>Extension of programs relating to autism</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2602EA213B84C2594E30D8A4658EA7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Developmental disabilities surveillance and research program</header><text>Section 399AA(e) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280i">42 U.S.C. 280i(e)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1296403C173846BBB1F52D8017329000"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Autism education, early detection, and intervention</header><text>Section 399BB(g) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280i-1">42 U.S.C. 280i–1(g)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94495F0D0D46476DA8F4E49DF8B357A1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interagency autism coordinating committee</header><text>Section 399CC(f) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280i-2">42 U.S.C. 280i–2(f)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6B1ECB5D74F84D0685AA9EECD3E844F0"><enum>202.</enum><header>Extension of authority to issue priority review vouchers to encourage treatments for rare pediatric diseases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 529(b)(5) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360ff">21 U.S.C. 360ff(b)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>December 20, 2024</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB92BCA752C83407AB52658B89ACB5ACE"><enum>203.</enum><header>No Surprises Act implementation funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 118(a) of title I of division BB of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>through 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>through September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section></subtitle> <subtitle id="HCB4DF729E0C945658A784B0D61BDBB11" style="OLC"><enum>B</enum><header>Medicaid</header> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31DD3FBB42AA41D19F8DADB9E632F57F"><enum>211.</enum><header>Medicaid funding for the Northern Mariana Islands</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1108(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1308">42 U.S.C. 1308</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE37747D0D284E4CB4383AEC3C19DBBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and (5)</quote> and inserting <quote>, (5), and (14)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H564D212D0924467FBDC238F6C5202D90"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86281B2D0CE046B4A4ECF5671BA4CEC5"> 
<paragraph id="H02EFCCB1541E4C87B727ADF37477E275"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Additional increase for the Northern Mariana Islands</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96CBA1FEA68544B1B876DBD88FD3A741"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary shall increase the total amount otherwise determined under this subsection for the Northern Mariana Islands for the period beginning on October 1, 2022, and ending on September 30, 2024, by $27,100,000.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4BBD27A84586497DA0A5630A5101FB8C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>The increase described in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="H07399D339D094CE8821EDF61F660E662"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall apply to the total amount certified by the Secretary under title XIX for payment to the Northern Mariana Islands for services attributable to fiscal year 2023 or 2024, notwithstanding that payments for any such services are made by the Northern Mariana Islands in fiscal year 2025; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFC4691695FA24BDD946E72BB7AE01B07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be in addition to the amount calculated under paragraph (2) for the Northern Mariana Islands for fiscal years 2023 and 2024 and shall not be taken into account in calculating an amount under paragraph (2) for the Northern Mariana Islands for fiscal year 2025 or a subsequent fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></subtitle> 
<subtitle style="OLC" commented="no" level-type="subsequent" id="H5E9AB08E454447F2A9E2AC315290874D"><enum>C</enum><header>Medicare</header> 
<section id="H0A41B7EC520B49B9B34482AC33B20247" commented="no"><enum>221.</enum><header>Revising phase-in of Medicare clinical laboratory test payment changes</header> 
<subsection id="H83F1B70B49924BCCA4CD131DF40C547B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Revised phase-in of reductions from private payor rate implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1834A(b)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m-1">42 U.S.C. 1395m–1(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H96318A1E3317442FB2FF8A1D34256048" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>2027</quote> and inserting <quote>2028</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H665F2B3526F04134A34827D6E2305BDC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subparagraph id="H14712EE669AC43C6AD63EB459F0F14A8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>2024</quote> and inserting <quote>2025</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H28CE046F3F124243A14D95FCBD2EB7E7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>2025 through 2027</quote> and inserting <quote>2026 through 2028</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H337D4F2B30FA42BEA8401E2C9DB0D18A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revised reporting period for reporting of private sector payment rates for establishment of Medicare payment rates</header><text>Section 1834A(a)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m-1">42 U.S.C. 1395m–1(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7F126D3C90824965B183918DC4B8DB4D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>2024</quote> and inserting <quote>2025</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6463DD13C082470FAE2CFAAF9BAF51B8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>2025</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>2026</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HEC31E6ED933D4AE7999166335D70F00E"><enum>222.</enum><header>Medicare Improvement Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1898(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395iii">42 U.S.C. 1395iii(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2022, $0</quote> and inserting <quote>2026, $3,197,000,000</quote>.</text></section></subtitle></title> <title id="HFC79C92491AC47409822557F34A33413"><enum>III</enum><header>VETERANS EXTENDERS</header> <subtitle id="H8FC4E18A74FA496BBFD6D7B9186AA609"><enum>A</enum><header>Health Care</header> <section id="H424D1D6724794801B91601CCDD8C24BE"><enum>301.</enum><header>Extension of authority for collection of copayments for hospital care and nursing home care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1710(f)(2)(B) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H84B871F78C3442A9B55B6E40194FBD85"><enum>302.</enum><header>Extension of requirement to provide nursing home care to certain veterans with service-connected disabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1710A(d) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H43EC460D6DFC4FBCB3D5F0BCBA60735B"><enum>303.</enum><header>Extension of expansion of rural access network for growth enhancement program of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(d) of the Sgt. Ketchum Rural Veterans Mental Health Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/21">Public Law 117–21</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1712A">38 U.S.C. 1712A</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>2024</quote> and inserting <quote>2025</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H4AF10EE5C9A34A46B4679F97F57AEAD1"><enum>304.</enum><header>Extension of pilot program to provide veterans access to complementary and integrative health programs through animal therapy, agritherapy, sports and recreation therapy, art therapy, and posttraumatic growth programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203(d)(1) of the Scott Hannon Veterans Mental Health Care Improvement Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/171">Public Law 116–171</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1712A">38 U.S.C. 1712A</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>for a three-year period beginning on the commencement of the pilot program</quote> and inserting <quote>until September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD78F38ACB68B493991D8995BE962F5D8"><enum>305.</enum><header>Extension of authority for joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs medical facility demonstration fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1704(e) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/84">Public Law 111–84</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 2573), as most recently amended by section 104 of division E of the Continuing Appropriations and Ukraine Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/180">Public Law 117–180</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 2137), is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section></subtitle> 
<subtitle id="H59B2F1A203B741B08FA682BE2166D4D5"><enum>B</enum><header>Memorial affairs</header> 
<section id="HF48DF2BE215E4B6EAF057ACCF0D10E88"><enum>311.</enum><header>Extension of entitlement to memorial headstones and markers for commemoration of veterans and certain individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2306(b)(2) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>October 1, 2024</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB71961EE56794588A7CD25C72C932D24"><enum>312.</enum><header>Extension of authority to bury remains of certain spouses and children in national cemeteries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2402(a)(5) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>October 1, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HF3BD7EB84F7C4249A9B9C13571ED961D" commented="no"><enum>313.</enum><header>Authority for use of flat grave markers at Santa Fe National Cemetery, New Mexico</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2404(c)(2) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB0B37C5F7B7543EAAB67623841C48CBD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2EF0EBE5F5143808165AABA533C6E7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C4F9D9290C24E2D9C70C05B5833B6E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H697FE53CEDF24C35BB11D7A812A1EC5C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H59F9E848DEAD4DC99346C42469132C94" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of Santa Fe National Cemetery, New Mexico, the Secretary may provide for flat grave markers in any section of such cemetery in which flat markers were in use on December 22, 2023.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></subtitle> <subtitle id="HCACDC97876844C51AF74243A8041AE47"><enum>C</enum><header>Homelessness</header> <section id="H2EADA2CD0A9B41C1ADFF979F95152E3D"><enum>321.</enum><header>Extension of authority to provide assistance for specially adapted housing for disabled veterans residing temporarily in housing owned by a family member</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2102A(e) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>December 31, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3192EB5C4E14495A3BAA140349F2235"><enum>322.</enum><header>Extension of authority for specially adapted housing assistive technology grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2108(g) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9571BD20E62B4F97A195659459A316D6"><enum>323.</enum><header>Extension of authorization of appropriations for homeless women veterans and homeless veterans with children reintegration grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2021A(f)(1) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>2024</quote> and inserting <quote>2025</quote>.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8A4FFD775DF4DC388ABBEF6655BBC3E"><enum>324.</enum><header>Extension of authority for treatment and rehabilitation for seriously mentally ill and homeless veterans</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D5D533E63BF458EBD56ED0C9873A013"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2031(b) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H29B5C9A43DE049858BA29CEACD346A2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional services at certain locations</header><text>Section 2033(d) of such title is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H483994428CE24FDA89B816D8341011CC"><enum>325.</enum><header>Extension of funding for financial assistance for supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CD907E4EA9146C4BDDCAE02EE00A426"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2044(e)(H) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>2024</quote> and inserting <quote>2025</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AF301BF54864B95A02D54A323212CBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Section 2044(e) of such title is amended by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (H) as paragraphs (1) through (8), respectively.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2DFEA2F105E45D3876423336A7A45E2"><enum>326.</enum><header>Extension of funding for grant program for homeless veterans with special needs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2061(d)(1) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>2024</quote> and inserting <quote>2025</quote>.</text></section></subtitle> <subtitle id="H7280577182E7451982E0B6AF801158FF"><enum>D</enum><header>Other Authorities</header> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB1264695DFD4F11BFBBC42398F0072E"><enum>331.</enum><header>Extension of authority to transport individuals to and from Department of Veterans Affairs facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 111A(a)(2) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H08BF5BB0F49E4E0C9B4D0D349591B0C6"><enum>332.</enum><header>Extension of testimonial subpoena authority of Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 312(d)(7)(A) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>May 31, 2025</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28FFB556E8F54482A48230BE9B984430"><enum>333.</enum><header>Extension of authority to maintain regional office in the Republic of the Philippines</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 315(b) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H3B648BFD1E40465CB658581A246713D5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>334.</enum><header>Extension and modification of authority for monthly assistance allowance for disabled veterans training in Paralympic and Olympic sports program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 322 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H96BA19CED4E7487AABE4C04E1C5BBD6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the United States Olympic Committee</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the United States Olympic &amp; Paralympic Committee</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F98D6D7507D4E41B24AEA100E76826F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>Veterans Benefits Administration</quote> and inserting <quote>Veterans Health Administration</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D7897E91BDC406392D2310304853F68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by amending paragraph (4) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45EF3E4C5F524FC2B6B0AFD0AC02C0F8"> 
<paragraph id="HA42D28CC0EDE4E408D1ECB9D22D14D97" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD57C70B015E043FBB26CB9BA309FCE4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For each of fiscal years 2010 through 2023, $2,000,000.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C460243EBBD40CAB70F04BA8E68578D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of fiscal years 2024 through 2027, $2,500,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFFB448B363D424B93234629780FF789"><enum>335.</enum><header>Extension of authority for report on equitable relief provided due to administrative error</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 503(c) of title 38, United States Code, is amended, in the second sentence, by striking <quote>December 31, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2025</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H45D4B801F31B482192DEFD79C738B778" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>336.</enum><header>Modification of certain housing loan fees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The loan fee table in section 3729(b)(2) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>November 15, 2031</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>November 29, 2031</quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11E1487640D44321A8D76BCF7E7EB355"><enum>337.</enum><header>Extension of authority for transfer of real property</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8118(a)(5) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HCC9970772BCC41149A3F7C90058BF751" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>338.</enum><header>Extension of requirements relating to Chief Financial Officer of the Department</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7103 of the Johnny Isakson and David P. Roe, M.D. Veterans Health Care and Benefits Improvement Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/315">Public Law 116–315</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>for fiscal year 2022 and each of the next three subsequent fiscal years</quote> and inserting <quote>for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029</quote>.</text></section></subtitle></title> <title id="HB53337CB6E094AB3988A90EBCD0264CE"><enum>IV</enum><header>BUDGETARY EFFECTS</header> <section id="HD2E69CD19868404F940DF9BD1E6580C4"><enum>401.</enum><header>Budgetary effects</header> <subsection id="H8A7F3C2D251E426E8F3F0416DD0093BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statutory PAYGO scorecards</header><text>The budgetary effects of this division shall not be entered on either PAYGO scorecard maintained pursuant to section 4(d) of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5B4DB4E8992C49CC8B772D64C91CB16E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Senate PAYGO scorecards</header><text>The budgetary effects of this division shall not be entered on any PAYGO scorecard maintained for purposes of section 4106 of H. Con. Res. 71 (115th Congress).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H987CCF44B027433F99E3652DF247BBA1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Classification of budgetary effects</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule 3 of the Budget Scorekeeping Guidelines set forth in the joint explanatory statement of the committee of conference accompanying Conference Report 105–217 and section 250(c)(8) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985, the budgetary effects of this division shall not be estimated—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4209C9644CFB4A8FB0EDF34FCF0F3C48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for purposes of section 251 of such Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7A2FEAE03DD4B8894C958E4E9CC9B7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for purposes of an allocation to the Committee on Appropriations pursuant to section 302(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H651132CF9FF649D9BC4D13FB12E6B571"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for purposes of paragraph (4)(C) of section 3 of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 as being included in an appropriation Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title></division> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

