<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="HA180E861DF664CAB938FE707EEEC4872" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 9468 ENR: Veterans Benefits Continuity and Accountability Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2024</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Eighteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Wednesday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-four</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9468</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Making supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2024, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H543F0839027A4FE28C770B30C9FEB01F" style="appropriations"> 
<section id="H2ABAA8CA3DB744B383D03ABC5DF91ABD" section-type="undesignated-section" indent="left-margin" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2024, and for other purposes, namely:</text></section> <section id="LEXA-Repairidf0c80bbe31a64f03b34baebb923e3547" section-type="undesignated-section"><appropriations-major id="HB752294B6C1E4D089EFC9C7712814CF7"><header>Department of Veterans Affairs</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HF1C1E27AD2F34F17BBB2E98F23F3423C"><header>Veterans Benefits Administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HFBD0A60D16E44989B3EBD5C5BDC1FD39"><header>Compensation and Pensions</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HB65931548953469A999E3B1E4FBF5541"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Compensation and Pensions</quote>, $2,285,513,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HDE5CFE1207B74F66B291402B52EF1893"><header>Veterans Benefits Administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HB24E2D1C48A14E85B77C41811DEEE349"><header>Readjustment Benefits</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H82DC1E0C8A3444DBA96E622E5F2E35A6"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Readjustment Benefits</quote>, $596,969,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H03D541FC231841B8B3A1CD08BF28C479"><header>General Provisions—This Act</header></appropriations-major></section> <section id="HBB335855BE5A434AAD05679ADBA1C30C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>101.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each amount appropriated or made available by this Act is in addition to amounts otherwise appropriated for the fiscal year involved.</text></section> 
<section id="H488110B6435546DF8B710494E9F63974" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>102.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise provided for by this Act, the additional amounts appropriated by this Act to appropriations accounts shall be available under the authorities and conditions applicable to such appropriations accounts for fiscal year 2024.</text></section> <section id="HEF47D57861874627883F74C5EFDA25D3"><enum>103.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1E71594B773D4D768B8484318643E84F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Budget formulation and forecasting</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations and the Committees on Veterans Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report detailing corrections the Department will make to improve forecasting, data quality and budget assumptions relating to budget submissions for funds provided under the headings <quote>Compensations and Pensions</quote> and <quote>Readjustment Benefits</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF946DC6FC0184083B33C5F9B0C0928AE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations and the Committees on Veterans Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on status of funds made available under the headings <quote>Compensations and Pensions</quote> and <quote>Readjustment Benefits</quote> for fiscal years 2024, 2025, and 2026 in this or any other Act: <italic>Provided,</italic> That such report shall be updated and submitted to such Committees every 90 days thereafter until September 30, 2026, and shall include information detailing any changes to estimates or assumptions on obligations and expenditures, including data supporting these changes.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HBC60B5046F8D470E880EF4E5A8C2D6C3"><enum>104.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA3D13E34A7294EDF94CCEFDD183B12AC"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a review of the circumstances surrounding and the underlying causes of the announced funding shortfall for the Veterans Benefits Administration for fiscal year 2024 described in the letter to Congress from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on July 19, 2024, and the announced funding shortfall for the Veterans Health Administration in fiscal year 2025 described in the letter to Congress from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on July 31, 2024.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFD0A9FC71297457CA9EFEB3F17E554BF"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Relating to the shortfall in the funding of the Veterans Benefits Administration in fiscal year 2024 and the expected shortfall in the funding of the Veterans Health Administration in fiscal year 2025, the review shall include, but not be limited to: a comparison of monthly obligations and expenditures in relevant accounts against the spend plan of the Department; the reasons for any significant diversions of obligations or expenditures from the spend plan; an analysis of the accuracy of projections and estimates relevant to such diversions; and any other matter determined relevant by the Inspector General.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD85CA20F9CCC4FAF94658F3F6B383E4A"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Relating to the expected shortfall in the funding of the Veterans Health Administration in fiscal year 2025, the review also shall include: any changes, abnormalities, or significant events as determined significant by the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs in the transfer, reallocation, or other movement of funding between or within the Central Office, a Veterans Integrated Service Network, a facility, a program or office, a special purpose fund, the Veterans Equitable Resource Allocation process, or the Medical Center Allocation System.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2FA4EE45175D434490F7C573AC91408C"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Actions the Department of Veterans Affairs can take to improve the accuracy of supporting information submitted under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, with respect to the Department of Veterans Affairs and to prevent funding shortfalls for the Department.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3E80ECC8BF1041F08905AB25B7900A50"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations and the Committees on Veterans Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report detailing the conduct and findings of the review.</text></subsection></section> 
<section section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8EA8F13C186F4259BB62F98FEED21AE3"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Benefits Continuity and Accountability Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2024</short-title></quote>.</text></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

